A new era is born.
Jurassic World Rebirth is a science fiction, adventure,
action film directed by Gareth Edwards.
Five years after the events of Jurassic World Dominion, covert operations expert Zora Bennett is contracted to lead a
skilled team on a top-secret mission to secure genetic material from the world's three most massive dinosaurs.
When Zora's operation intersects with a civilian family whose boating expedition was capsized, they all find themselves stranded on an
island where they come face-to-face with a sinister, shocking discovery that's been hidden from the world for decades.
Zora Bennett, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Duncan Kincaid, played by Mahershala Ali.
Dr. Henry Loomis, played by Jonathan Bailey.
Martin Krebs, played by Rupert Friend.
Reuben Delgado, played by Manuel Garcia-Rulfo.
Teresa Delgado, played by Luna Blaise.
Jurassic World Rebirth is a 2025 American science fiction action film
directed by Gareth Edwards and written by David Koepp.
It is the fourth Jurassic World film, as well as the seventh
installment overall in the Jurassic Park franchise.
The film features Scarlett Johansson, Mahershala Ali, Jonathan
Bailey, Rupert Friend, Manuel Garcia-Rulfo, and Ed Skrein.
In Jurassic World Rebirth, the world's de-extinct dinosaurs live around the
equator, which provides the last viable climate for them to survive.
A team travels to a former island research facility where three specific gigantic species of dinosaurs
reside, with the goal of extracting samples that are vital for a heart disease treatment.
The team also rescues a shipwrecked family, and both groups struggle
to survive after becoming stranded on the island.
Work on the film began shortly after the release of Jurassic World Dominion, when executive producer
Steven Spielberg recruited Koepp to help him develop a new installment in the series.
Koepp previously co-wrote the original Jurassic Park film (1993) and
wrote its sequel, The Lost World: Jurassic Park (1997).
Development of Rebirth was first reported in January 2024.
Edwards was hired as director a month later, and
casting commenced shortly thereafter.
Principal photography took place in Thailand, Malta, and the
United Kingdom from June to September 2024.
Jurassic World Rebirth premiered on June 17, 2025, at Odeon Luxe Leicester Square in London, and
was released in the United States and Canada by Universal Pictures on July 2.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, though some
deemed it an improvement over previous entries.
It became the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2025, and grossed over $869
million worldwide against a budget of $180–225 million.
At the 98th Academy Awards, it was nominated for Best Visual Effects, making it the first film in Jurassic
Park franchise since The Lost World (1997) to receive an Oscar nomination in any category.
The film explores themes of island, secret mission, stranded, dinosaur, family.
The tone is thought_provoking.